Yilun Jin | Curriculum Vitae

Department of CSE, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology Hong Kong SAR – China

I am currently a PhD student from Department of Computer Science and Engineering, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong SAR, advised by Prof. Qiang Yang and co-advised by Prof. Kai Chen. My current research interests lie in the field of Federated Learning, including algorithms and privacy & security. I am also interested in information network mining, including Graph Representation Learning, Graph Neural Networks, etc*.

Education

Ph.D. Student, Dept. of CSE, HKUST

Hong Kong SAR

Computer Science and Engineering

9.2019-

Advisor: Prof. Qiang Yang, Prof. Kai Chen (co-advisor).

B. S., School of EECS, Peking University

Beijing, China

9.2015-7.2019

Computer Science, GPA: 3.7/4.0

Advisor: Prof. Guojie Song

Selected courses: Advanced Algebra, Mathematical Analysis, Convex Optimization, Compiler Design.

B. Economics, National School of Development, Peking University

Economics, GPA: 3.7/4.0

Beijing, China 9.2016–7.2019

Selected courses: Intermediate Macro- & Micro-Economics, Econometrics, Financial Economics, Money and Banking, Special Topics on Reform in China

University of California, San Diego

La Jolla, USA

Exchange Student, GPA: 3.93/4.0

9.2017-12.2017

Courses: Computer Operating System, Machine Learning, Recommender System and Web Mining

Experiences

WeBank Shenzhen, China

Internship, advised by Dr. Lixin Fan

6.2020-12.2020

Research on federated learning, adversarial machine learning, and machine learning privacy.

SenseTime Beijing, China

Research Internship on Video analysis

3.2018-6.2018

Implemented content-aware collaborative filtering based video recommendation algorithm, along with a dataset for video recommendation, consisting both video corpus and interaction data.

University of California, San Diego

La Jolla, USA

Research Intern, advised by Prof. Julian McAuley

7.2018-9.2018

Research intern on deep, visually and temporally aware recommender systems and user preference modeling. Extending existing work *Neural Collaborative Filtering (He and Chua, 2017)* to make it temporally-aware.

^{*}Last Updated Jan. 2021

Peking University, China

Beijing, China

Research Assistant, advised by Prof. Guojie Song

10.2018-9.2019

Research on a wide range of topics through graph representation learning, including temporal aware, community aware and memory adaptive network embeddings. Several topics on Graph Neural Networks are also involved. See *Publications* for details.

Publications

Graph Structural-topic Neural Network

Qingqing Long*, **Yilun Jin***, Guojie Song, Yi Li, Wei Lin

8.2020

In the 26th SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD), 2020.

EPNE: Evolutionary Pattern Preserving Network Embedding

[`] Junshan Wang^{*}, **Yilun Jin**^{*}, Guojie Song, Xiaojun Ma

6.2020

In the 24th European Conference on Artificial Intelligence (ECAI), 2020.

GraLSP: Graph Neural Networks with Local Structural Patterns

Yilun Jin, Guojie Song, Chuan Shi

2.2020

In the 34th AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2020.

GraphMSE: Efficient Meta-path Selection in Semantically Aligned Feature Space

4. for Graph Neural Networks

Yi Li, **Yilun Jin**, Guojie Song, Chuan Shi, Zihao Zhu, Yiming Wang

2.2021

To appear in the 35th AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2021.

Domain Adaptive Classification on Heterogeneous Information Networks

Shuwen Yang, Guojie Song, Yilun Jin, Lun Du

7.2020

In the 29th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI-PRICAI), 2020.

Active Domain Transfer on Network Embedding

Lichen Jin, Yizhou Zhang, Guojie Song, **Yilun Jin**

4.2020

In the Web Conference (TheWebConf, a.k.a. WWW), 2020.

Hierarchical Community Structure Preserving Network Embedding: A Subspace

7. Approach

Qingqing Long, Yiming Wang, Lun Du, Guojie Song, Yilun Jin, Wei Lin

11.2019

In the 28th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM), 2019.

Best Research Paper Runner-up

DANE: Domain Adaptive Network Embedding

Yizhou Zhang, Guojie Song, Lun Du, Shuwen Yang, **Yilun Jin**

8.2019

In the 28th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI). 2019.

9. KecureBoost: A Lossless Federated Learning Framework

Kewei Cheng, Tao Fan, Yilun Jin, Yang Liu, Tianjian Chen, Qiang Yang

8.2019

The 1st International Workshop on Federated Machine Learning for User Privacy and Data Confidentiality, in conjunction with IJCAI 2019

(* stands for *Equal Contribution*.)

Technical and Personal skills

- o Mathematics Background: Discrete Mathematics, Advanced Algebra, Convex Optimization, Mathematical Analysis, Probability and Statistics.
- o Programming Languages: C, C++, Python (TensorFlow, PyTorch), Java, LATEX, SQL

- Language Skills: Chinese (native speaker), English (proficient with speaking 26 in TOEFL, analytical writing 5.0 in GRE)
 - I take charge of writing in most of the publications listed above.
- o General Skills: Self motivation. Work well in a team.

Teaching

- **Teaching Assistant**, *Practice of Programming in C++*, Peking University, Spring 2019
- Teaching Assistant, COMP4631: Computer and Communication Security, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Spring 2020
- Teaching Assistant, COMP5631: Cryptography and Security, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Fall 2020
- Teaching Assistant, COMP6211G: Federated Learning, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Spring 2021

Services

- Program Committee Member: TheWebConf 2020, ICONIP 2020, AAAI 2021, IJCAI 2021, NeurIPS 2021
- o Journal Reviewer: IEEE BigData (2021).
- o Secondary Reviewer: ICLR 2020, AAAI 2020, ACL 2020, NeurIPS 2020.

Awards

- o AAAI Student Scholarship, AAAI, 2020
- o Best Research Paper Runner-up, CIKM Research Track, 2019
- Award for Research Excellence, Peking University, 2018
- o Merit Student, Peking University, 2017
- Huawei Scholarship, Peking University, 2017
- Yu Minhong Scholarship for overseas exchange, Peking University, 2017
- o Founder Scholarship, Peking University, 2016
- Award for Academic Excellence, Peking University, 2016

Miscellaneous

o Aside from academic activities, I also participate in activities related to civil aviation. I am a distinguished author of civil aviation in *zhihu*, a question-answering website similar to *Quora*. I am also a member of *ACICFG*, a group for caption making of documentary *Air Crash Investigation*, whose works have been published to video websites including *acfun* and *bilibili*.